<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<workzag-jobs>

    
        <position>
            <id>935768</id>
                            <subcompany>mrge</subcompany>
                                        <office>Berlin / Hamburg</office>
                                                    <department>Engineering</department>
                                        <recruitingCategory>Business Itelligence</recruitingCategory>
            
            <name>Head of Data (m/f/d) - Berlin/Hamburg based (Hybrid)</name>

                            <jobDescriptions>
                                                                    <jobDescription>
                            <name>Looking for an exciting challenge?</name>
                            <value>
<![CDATA[
                                Join us on our mission to become a global champion in commerce advertising and performance marketing.<br> <br>Backed by our investor Waterland Private Equity, our four companies are digidip, shopping24, Sourceknowledge and Yieldkit form mrge. Together, we are building and scaling technology platforms that all share the goal of connecting advertisers and publishers ​in a manner beneficial to both parties.<br><br>We are an international, multilingual team with flat hierarchies. Our teams work with a high degree of independence, both from offices in Hamburg and Berlin, as well as remotely.<br> <br>Our culture runs on trust, friendliness, and collegiality, fostering a positive work atmosphere.<br>Working with us is easy and fun – just ask our clients, who we help to reach their goals in an uncomplicated, reliable way. <br>In close cooperation with our partners, we provide advertising formats that offer genuine relevance for our users and, as a result, lead to higher sales.<br> <br><br>We would be delighted if you joined us ​as our Head of Data!
]]>
                            </value>
                        </jobDescription>
                                                                                            <jobDescription>
                            <name>Your Tasks:</name>
                            <value>
<![CDATA[
                                <p>We're looking for an experienced Head of Data to lead our team in developing and implementing a robust data strategy that aligns with our business objectives and drives organisational growth. Key responsibilities include effectively communicating insights to stakeholders, partnering with business leaders to use data to drive results, and fostering a product-driven mindset to create solutions that meet customer needs and align with business goals.</p><ul><li>Lead the development of our data strategy and roadmap in alignment with company objectives, and effectively communicate this vision to various stakeholders.</li><li>Mentor and develop a team of data professionals, including data scientists, analysts, and engineers, and provide ongoing support to foster their growth and skills development.</li><li>Establish a self-service data platform for analytics, ensuring data accessibility and comprehensibility for real-time decision-making and improved outcomes.</li><li>Engage hands-on in data management, advanced analytics, and project delivery, addressing technical challenges and prioritising tangible results and value through data-driven initiatives alongside leadership duties.</li><li>Cultivate a product-driven mindset, concentrating on creating and refining products or solutions that meet customer needs and align with business goals.</li><li>Communicate insights to stakeholders clearly and actionably, collaborating closely with business leaders to leverage data for driving business outcomes.</li><li>Stay updated on industry trends and best practices, continuously learning about the ad tech industry and the target market's needs.</li></ul>
]]>
                            </value>
                        </jobDescription>
                                                                                            <jobDescription>
                            <name>Your Profile:</name>
                            <value>
<![CDATA[
                                <ul><li>Bachelor's degree in a related field (e.g. computer science, data science, statistics)</li><li>8+ years of experience in data management and advanced analytics, with at least 3 years of experience in a leadership role</li><li>Strong understanding of cloud-based data platforms and experience working with large and complex data sets</li><li>Proven track record of leading and developing high-performing teams</li><li>Excellent communication and interpersonal skills, with the ability to effectively present findings and insights to a variety of audiences</li><li>Passion for staying up-to-date on industry trends and best practices, and continuously learning about the ad tech industry and the needs of the target market</li><li>Fluent in English, German skills are a plus</li></ul>
]]>
                            </value>
                        </jobDescription>
                                                                                            <jobDescription>
                            <name>Your Opportunity:</name>
                            <value>
<![CDATA[
                                <ul><li>Take an active role in shaping an innovative, growth-orientated international corporate group from its early stages; seize the opportunity to become irreplaceable!</li><li>Take on responsibility as you become an important part of a young, ambitious, and friendly team with a shared desire to develop its skills.</li><li>Enjoy opportunities to work independently, with flexible hours and hybrid remote/office working options.</li><li>Enjoy top-notch employee benefits: 30 paid vacation days, the latest tech, individual development plan, prepaid spending card (50€ monthly budget) and much more</li><li>Take your skills, talents, and career to the next level as you grow with us. </li></ul><strong>Have we convinced you? Then we can’t wait to read your application!</strong><br><br>All our employees have equal career opportunities at mrge, regardless of gender, origin, ethnicity, religion, sexual orientation, age, or other personal attributes.<br>Candidates will be considered and selected equally based on their skills, qualification, and the needs of the company.<br>We know that experience and skills are matters of development and gain while working. Therefore, we encourage you to apply even if your profile does not meet 100% of the requirements for this position.
]]>
                            </value>
                        </jobDescription>
                                                            </jobDescriptions>
            
                            <employmentType>permanent</employmentType>
            
                            <seniority>experienced</seniority>
            
                            <schedule>full-time</schedule>
            
                            <yearsOfExperience>5-7</yearsOfExperience>
            
                            <keywords>backend,software engineer,marketing,agile</keywords>
            
                            <occupation>general_and_other_engineering</occupation>
            
                            <occupationCategory>engineering</occupationCategory>
            
                            <createdAt>2022-12-22T16:04:21+00:00</createdAt>
            
            
        </position>


    
</workzag-jobs>
